[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to tric
senst tasa automation tutorial as you
all know I've already published 61
YouTube videos covering beginner level
intermediate level and advanced level
concepts of triage
Taska from couple of days onwards have
started teaching you the realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of obstacles and how can
we solve those
obstacles while automating your test
cases by using tricentis tasa please do
subscribe to the channel click on Bell
icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos don't
forget to like and share the
video this is our lesson 16 2 in terms
of overall tric Centrist task automation
tutorial and this is our obstacle 20 in
terms of realtime scenarios in this
lesson I'm going to teach you how can we
solve an
obstacle by using random mathematical
operations and evaluation tool for
calculations while automating your test
cases now let us go to obstacle list and
understand what is the obst obstacle
that we need to solve for in detail this
is our obstacle which is named as math
and which is categorized as hard so let
us go for
it please complete the operation listed
below and enter it in result box okay so
here you can see it as very simple but
it's not that simple okay okay it is
hard okay why because these
numbers
are dynamic in nature not only numbers
your operator or Opera and also a
dynamic in
nature okay so let me just click on try
again so if you click on try again see
now your operator is plus 7 + 11 let's
try again now your operator is mod 38
mod 10 right so you have four different
operations one is
multiplication which is see here this is
your multiplication right 23 multiply 20
and you have addition and you have
subtraction and you have mod okay so the
you so your operator is dynamic and your
random number one random number two also
Dynamic now you need to automate this
particular test case to print the
correct result based on the operator and
based on the random numbers so how can
we do that let us go to prasa as usual
what we are going to do we going to
start scanning all we are going to start
scanning the objects for this particular
scenario right click on obstacle folder
select scan select application
so this is my application select the
application and click on
scan it opens your X scan now what are
the objects that you would like to scan
one is random number one random number
two your operator and your result edit
box right so for that so here I can see
random number one this is my random
number
one and this is my
operator and this is our random number
two and this is the result where we are
going to
enter right so we captured all the
objects that are required to automate
our test case now let us rename this
module with the name of your obstacle
copy this
this and rename the module and save the
module and close your X scan let's go
back to trient tasa and you can see this
is our obstacle this is our module that
we captured the last one double click on
this see here I can
see random number 1 2 to operator result
so I would like to rename this instead
of 36 I'm going to name this as
random number
one and this is our
operand right
operator
operand and this is
my random number
two right and this is result renamed
them now let us go back to our left side
test case section so under obstacle
folder like right click on test case
folder and create new test case name
this as the obstacle name right once
that is done now let us double click on
this particular test
case and now let us automate our test
case for that drag this and drop onto
your test case drag the module and drop
onto your test case Okay so once we drop
onto the test case now what we need to
do we need to capture this random
number into a buffer you need to capture
this second random number also into your
buffer and also we need to
capture the upper hand also into a
buffer so hence here what I'm going to
do I'm going to enter a buffer name
called
random one this is my buffer and action
mode becomes
buffer and this is my upper hand upper
hand I'm going to say and capture the
same into
buffer and this is my random
two and capture this also into a
buffer so we captur the values into
buffer now what we need to do to enter
the value into result based on the
operator your result will be published
right so that means we have four
different operators let's do first for
the addition that means you have how to
perform mathematical
operation based on your
operator so what we need to do we have
to use if condition if operator is plus
write your math condition if operator is
minus and you need to WR you need to
write math function for subtraction if
operator is mult multiplication you need
to write math function for
multiplication in the same way for mod
so for that let's go back here now into
the
module what we need to do
here we need to introduce if else
condition right so what I'm going to do
right click on this particular test case
right click on this and you need to call
for create if
statement I like this one
if what is the condition to evaluate the
operator right I need to evaluate the
operator first if my operator is plus do
addition so like that I need to Define
for all four different operators let us
go back here under condition I would
like to use one standard module to
evaluate the expression what is that
control t p tbox evaluation
tool select this tbox evaluation tool
and
here I would like to use the action mode
as verify because I'm going to verify
what is the operator right what I'm
going to do
here under expression I'm going to call
the buffer where I'm storing the
operator open curly braces capital B
operat
and open Square braces open curly braces
so
if here for any tbox Evolution right so
when you are using your tbox Evolution
tool under expression I would recommend
you guys to use single codes remember
that under expression you need to use
single codes if my
buffer equal to
again single Cotes plus I'm verifying if
my buffer value is equal to
plus I'm verifying this if this is plus
because my here you can here I can see
this expression has plus I'm going to
write one condition for plus okay
addition if my operator is plus then
drag this module
onto this
condition if operator is plus now I need
to write the math expression for
addition where under
result so what I'm going to do here open
curly
braces math function I'm calling math
function what is math function I'm going
to write everything under these Square
braces
call my first
buffer random number one plus random
number two right that is my math
function because your operator is plus
so to call my first buffer open Square
braces capital B open sorry open curly
braces capital B open Square braces
random one close Square
braces and close cut cly braces this is
my first
buffer
Plus open curly braces capital B open
Square braces
random two this is my second buffer
close Square braces close curly braces
done and then close your math
function that's
it so here I have I have written one
condition what is that if my operator is
plus
perform addition math
function now save this one let me run
this my
first condition okay right click because
I can see here it
has plus symbol that's why this formula
works for me now let me run this
particular entire test case right click
and run in
scratchbook now your 36 + 13 is 49 right
that means whatever the expression we
wrote for my first condition which is
addition is correct now you can see the
operator got changed to multiplication
so that's why I need to
repeat this if condition four times I'm
going to copy
this I'm going to paste it
here I'm going to paste the same thing
three
times total four conditions now let me
expand now let me expand second
condition so
here if my expression
is
multiply right here my
math condition my math expression
becomes
multiply perfect this is my second
condition if operator
is multiply perform multiply operation
and
now the third one if my operator is
substract
right so
here
minus and do
subtraction
done now my fourth condition is
mod open
this if the operator is
mod and then perform mod
operation perfect so now we are ready
with all our four
conditions right
so so now let us change this work state
as
completed save the test case so what I'm
going to do now I'm going to run the
same test case here now let us run the
test case multiple times to make sure it
works for all the operators right click
and run earlier the operator was plus
now the operator is
multiply see your multiplication
operation is successful let me retry
again now you can see your operator is
substraction let me run the T case
again it goes to your third condition
because your operator is
subtraction it entered
correctly now your operator is mod so
let me run this again now it should go
to your fourth condition if operator is
mod perform mod right click and run
see which is successful so let's go back
to my test case and let me explain again
okay what we
did so what we have done first we have
simply dragged and dropped our module
where I am
storing the random number one random
number two operator into buffer that's
it in the first step and in the second
step we are using IF then else condition
if my operator is I'm using tbox
evaluation tool under condition right
I'm evaluating the expression if my
operator is plus then what I did under
then condition under then I have again
dragged and dropped my
module and I've defined a math function
for
sum for addition by using the buffer
values that we stored in earlier step
right so now I have repeated the same
if than condition three more
times for three different operators and
Publishing the result based on the
operator or writing the math function
based on the operator so after defined
all the math expressions for four
different
operators and entering the result into
your result edit
box hope you all understand the concept
if you have any queries leave your
queries in the comment box I'll try to
respond to your queries thank you hope
you all understand how can we solve an
obstacle by using random mathematical
operations evaluation tool for
calculations why while automating your
test cases by using tricentis
Tas please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos don't forget to like and share
the video thank you
[Music]